Remember when I had a monkey?
我之前不是养过猴子？
What was I thinking?
我在想什么？
Hey,so,what's with the 20 percent tip? Did I do something wrong?
小费怎么才二十分？ 我做错事了吗？
20 percent is a pretty generous tip.
二十分很大方了
You know what's more generous? 50 percent!
你知道几分更大方？五十分
-You know what's even more generous? -I see where you're going.
你知道怎样更大方？ 我知道你想说什么了
What's up with the greed?
你干嘛这么贪？
I'm sorry.
好吧，对不起，只是…
I have to get new headshots made, and they're really expensive.
我得照新的大头照，但是好贵
I'm down to,like,three.
我只剩三张了
Actually,two, because one of them I blackened some teeth.
其实是两张，有一张的牙齿 被我涂黑…
Why'd I do that?
我秀逗啊
Isn't there something you can do to earn extra money?
你不能设法多赚一点吗？
Can't you pick up an extra shift here?
例如在这里多轮一班
Or,you know,I used to beg for money.
或是我以前当过乞丐
It helps if you've got a little of this going on.
如果能这样更有用
Wow! I still have it.
我现在还会
Don't you have an audition today? Maybe you'll get that job.
等等，你今天不是有试镜？ 也许你会入选
Wait a minute.
等等
I used to get medical experiments done on me.
我以前常参加医学实验
Finally,an explanation.
难怪变成这样
I used to get paid for all kinds of medical stuff.
不是，我以前常靠这个赚钱 记得吗？
Let's see... Well,I don't want to donate sperm again.
我想想，我不想再捐精了
I really prefer doing that at the home office.
那种事在家做比较好
Maybe they want some of my blood or spit or something,huh?
也许医院会要我的血或口水
-Joey? -Yeah.
乔伊？ 怎样？
What did I tell you about talking while working?
我说工作时跟朋友聊天会怎样
Do it?
干得好？
That guy's been waiting 10 minutes. He's complained about you three times.
那个人等咖啡等了10分钟 他抱怨了你三次
Now,where was l?
我讲到哪里？
The One With Unagi
本集播出：“鳗鱼力量”
rainystar压制iPod-MP4
What are you up to?
你们在忙什么？
We went to a self-defense class today.
我们今天去学防身术
Kicking a guy in the crotch all morning really takes it out of you.
对，踢了一早上的鼠蹊部 什么鸟气都没了
Takes it out of you?
那是你们
Now we can kick anybody's ass.
现在我们谁都能修理
After one class? I don't think so.
才一堂课？不会吧
You want to see me self-defend myself?
你想看我自卫吗？
Pretend you're a predator.
去假装你是性侵犯
Go on,I dare you!
有种就去
Of course you can defend yourself from an attack you know is coming.
你当然可以抵挡已知的攻击
That's not enough.
但那样还不够
Look,I studied karate for a long time.
我学了很久的空手道
And there's a concept you should be familiar with.
有个概念你们一定要了解
It's what the Japanese call unagi.
日文叫做unagi
Isn't that a kind of sushi?
那不是一种寿司吗？
No,it's a concept.
那是一种概念
Yeah,it is. It's freshwater eel.
是寿司没错，那是鳗鱼
Maybe it means that too.
或许是同一个字…
I would kill for a salmon-skin roll right now.
我现在好想吃鲑鱼握寿司
Fine,get attacked. I don't even care.
好，被攻击活该，我不在乎
Come on,Ross,we're sorry. Please tell us what it is.
罗斯，对不起，快告诉我们
Unagi is a state of total awareness.
Unagi是一种全知的境界
Only by achieving true unagi...
只有达到真正的unagi
can you be prepared for any danger that may befall you.
才能应付任何可能的危险
In case someone's trying to steal your bamboo sleeping mat...
你是说有人要偷你的竹席
or your kettle of fish?
或鱼壶的时候吗？
It's one thing being prepared for an attack against each other.
我是说应付彼此攻击是一回事
Whole other story being prepared for an attack. I don't know.. Surprise!
应付偷袭又是另一回事
You knew that was coming...
好，这次你们料到了
but that doesn't mean you have unagi.
但不表示你们有unagi
If we made reservations, we could have unagi in a half-hour.
知道吗？如果我们现在订位 半小时后就能吃到鳗鱼
-Is Monica here? -No.
摩妮卡在吗？ 不在
I need help. I don't know what to get for Valentine's Day.
帮个忙 我不知道该送什么情人节礼物
Valentine's Day was two weeks ago, so I wouldn't get her a calendar.
情人节已经过两星期了 我不会送她日历
She was working, so we're celebrating tonight.
她那天要上班，我们改今天过
Why don't you book a day for both of you at those romantic spas?
去帮你们一起订个SPA嘛
That's actually a good idea.
乔伊，这个主意很棒
And,of course,crotchless panties.
还有胯下开洞的内裤
As appealing as that sounds to her boyfriend...
虽然她的男朋友觉得很诱人…
and her brother...
她哥哥也是
We promised to make each other gifts this year.
但我们说好今年要自己做礼物
-I love that. -You guys!
我喜欢 真好
You can't make crotchless panties?
你不会做开洞的内裤？
You take scissors and cut..
拿一把剪刀给它剪…
Okay,okay,okay.
好好好
Making things sounds so much fun.
做礼物，听起来好好玩
I thought so too,until I papier-mached one of my eyes shut.
我也这么认为 直到我的眼睛糊到纸黏土
I love papier-mache! What did you make?
我喜欢纸黏土，你做了什么？
I made a flar-lar-lar.
我做了@#% ！
-What is that? -Nothing!
那是什么？ 什么也不是
So,what are you gonna do?
你要怎么办？
Have you made anything I can take credit for?
你们有没有做什么能借给我用
I have,I have! I started making little sock bunnies!
我有！我有！我做了袜子兔
Oh,for crying out loud!
了不起吧
Wait a minute. That is my sock!
等等，那是我的袜子
Now it's your little bunny friend.
现在它是你的兔兔朋友
Okay...
好
This actually is a flar-lar-lar.
这是一个@#% ！
Can I ask about the Valentine's Day gifts?
我能不能问你情人节礼物的事
-Yeah. -Do we have to make the entire thing?
可以啊 全都要自己做吗？
Yes. Did you forget to make yours?
当然，你忘了做吗？
Of course not.
当然没有
I just have to go to the place where I made it and pick it up.
我只是得去做的地方拿回来 好
I can't wait. It'll be the best Valentine's Day ever!
我好期待 这会是最棒的情人节
I can't believe it! Make the presents!
我居然忘了，要做礼物
-What? -Just so excited to make the presents!
什么？ 要做礼物好兴奋喔
真是的
Hi,I'm Joey Tribbiani.
你好，我是乔伊崔比亚尼
With all due respect, I'd like to donate some fluids.
我想捐赠一些体液
We're at the end of a research cycle and not looking for applicants now.
我们的研究刚告一段落 目前没有在找人
That's too bad. I've been saving up.
真可惜，我存了一阵子
You sure there's no studies I can participate in?
真的没有我能参加的研究？
-Here's a schedule. -Thanks.
这是接下来的一览表 谢谢
This one starts now.
这个已经开始了
Only identical twins are eligible. It's a twin study.
没错，但只限双胞胎 那是双胞胎研究
But it's $2000!
但是有2千块钱
Sorry.
抱歉
And this?
那...
"Testing the Effects of Joey Tribbiani on Attractive Nurse Receptionist."
乔伊崔比亚尼 对美女接待的影响力实验呢？
Results are back on that one. They're not good.
结果已经出来了，不太理想
-That was good. -Yeah.
Danger! Danger!
危险！危险
What the hell was that?
你搞什么啊？
A lesson in the importance of unagi.
让你们认识unagi的重要
You're a freak!
你变态
Perhaps.
或许吧
Now I'm curious.
我很好奇
At what point during those girlish screams would you have kicked my ass?
你们那样哀哀叫 什么时候才要修理我？
All right, so we weren't prepared!
好吧，我们没有准备
I'm sorry I had to take such drastic measures to make my point.
抱歉用这种方法传达我的重点
I just want you to be safe.
我是为你们的安全着想
Danger!
危险！
Ah-ha!
Unagi!
Unagi
“选角经纪公司”
2000 bucks is a lot of money.
2千块好多
I wish I had a twin.
真想有个双胞胎兄弟
Where could I find someone...
哪里才有...
who looks exactly like me?
跟我长得一样的人？
Chandler.
钱德
I sensed it was you.
我感觉到是你
What?
什么？
Unagi.
Unagi
I'm always aware.
我永远全知
Are you aware that unagi is an eel?
你知道unagi是鳗鱼吗？
-What's up? -I can't figure out what to make Monica.
什么事？ 我不知道该做什么礼物
Why don't you make her one of your little jokes?
你可以讲个笑话
I'm going crazy. Do you have anything homemade?
我快急死了，好吗？ 你有没有状似自制的东西？
You know what? She'd love this.
这个她一定会喜欢
It's a replica of Apollo 8. I made it in the sixth grade.
这是阿波罗八号的模型 我六年级做的
I could use that. I could say, "Your love sends me to the moon."
这个可以 我可以说你的爱让我飞上月亮
Except Apollo 8 didn't actually land on the moon.
可是阿波罗八号没有登陆月球
You can say, "Your love lets me orbit the moon twice and return safely."
不过你可以写你的爱 让我绕行月球两圈后顺利返航
I can't give this to her.
我不能送这个 为什么？
-Why not? -It says "Captain Ross" on the side.
因为旁边写着“罗斯队长”
And it says "I hate Monica" on the bottom.
底下写着“我讨厌摩妮卡”
Danger!
危险！
Salmon-skin roll.
鲑鱼握寿司
好…
Yes,honey, I made it myself.
没错，这是我自己做的
I can't do it. I can't do it.
我剪不下去，我剪不下去
A mixed tape! A mixed tape!
自己录的合辑
Hi! Ready to exchange gifts?
可以交换礼物了吗？
-Sure. You go first. -Okay,come here.
当然，你先 好，过来
Okay, it's not wrapped because I just finished it.
好 我没有包装，因为我刚完成 好
But I made you a tape of what I think are all romantic songs.
我录了一卷浪漫情歌给你
What a great gift!
好棒的礼物
Is "The Way You Look Tonight" on it?
有“你今晚的模样”吗？
We'll have to listen and see.
听了就知道
Oh,I love it! Thank you so much.
我好喜欢喔，谢谢你 不客气
You ready to open yours?
你要拆了吗？ 要
It's a sock bunny.
是袜子兔
Remember how I call you bunny?
对，我不是有叫你小兔兔？
Not really.
有吗？
I did one time. And I want to start doing it more.
我叫过一次，以后我想多叫
-That's what this is about. -I see.
所以做了袜子兔 我懂了
Phoebe makes sock bunnies.
菲比也有做袜子兔
No,she doesn't. What she makes,they're sock rabbits.
不，没有 菲比做的是袜子兔子
They're completely different. Okay,okay.
完全不一样…好吧
I didn't make it!
这不是我做的
I forgot about tonight and that we're supposed to make the presents.
我完全忘了今晚和做礼物的事
It's okay.
没关系，我…
No,it's not okay.
不，当然有关系
You're so incredible.
你那么…你那么用心
You went through all this time and effort to make this tape.
花那么多心血录情歌给我
I'll make this up to you. I will.
我要补偿你，我一定会的
I am going to cook you anything you want in here.
我会下厨房煮你想吃的菜
And I'm going to do anything you want in there.
进卧房玩你想玩的花样
Well, I did put a lot of thought into the tape.
我的确花了很多心血
You are way too young to have seen that.
你还小，不该看的
Your birthday's in a month and a half.
再1个半月就是你的生日
What if I forget to get you a present for that too?
要是我又忘记准备礼物呢？
You are totally and completely 100 percent forgiven.
我百分之百完全原谅你
We've got to wash that.
那个得拿去洗 没错
Remember that jacket you loved that was too expensive?
你不是看上一件外套 又嫌它太贵？
You have done enough.
你对我已经够好了
I'll wake up early and get it.
我要一早跑去买来送你
No,you don't.. Get it in black,not brown.
你不必… 买黑色，别买咖啡色
Your cake is ready.
你的蛋糕好了
It's like that old saying, "Have sex, eat some cake."
俗话说得好 做做爱，吃吃蛋糕
Hey,Mon. Hey,Chan. Just getting a soda.
小摩，老钱，我来拿汽水
Who the hell are you?
你是谁？
I'm Joey.
乔伊啊
How are you doing?
你好吗？
No! No! No! No! No!
错错错错错！
How you doing?
是你好吗
How you doing? Damn it, Carl! Go wait in the hall.
你好吗…真是的！去走廊等我
I've got to apologize on behalf of Carl.
我代替卡尔道歉
Who the hell is Carl?
卡尔是谁？
Did I not mention?
我没说吗？
Carl is a guy I hired to be my twin for a medical research project.
我找卡尔来演我的双胞胎兄弟 好参加医学研究
Sometimes the good ideas are right in front of you.
有时妙计就在眼前，是吧？
It sounds crazy, but it might work. The only problem is Carl's acting...
我知道很扯，但搞不好会成功 唯一的问题是卡尔的演技…
The only problem?
唯一的问题？
He's the reason I didn't get that big commercial a couple of years ago.
对，他害我两年前 痛失那支大广告，记得吗？
We were supposed to be brothers, but he messed up.
我们演兄弟，他却搞砸了
Can I get a piece of that cake?
我可以吃一小块蛋糕吗？
Pizza! We like pizza! Get out!
披萨，我们爱吃披萨 滚出去
-Pat Sajak? -Yep.
派特赛贾克？ 可以
-Alex Trebek? -Of course.
亚历崔贝克？ 当然
-Chuck Woolery? -Definitely.
恰克乌勒利？ 绝对行
You will not find a single game-show host whose ass I cannot kick.
所有的综艺节目主持人 我都能修理
-Say it! -Say we are unagi!
说 说我们是unagi
It's not something you are, it's something you have.
不是是不是，而是有没有
Say it!
快说
I could easily get out of this...
我可以轻易挣脱
but there's a chance you could get very, very hurt!
但你们可能会死得很惨
Carl,we're next. Now remember, what is this not gonna be?
接着就是我们 记住，这次不能怎样？
-Another Minute Maid fiasco. -That's right.
重蹈那次广告的覆辙 没错
And what are you not gonna do?
你不能怎样？
-I'm not gonna talk because.. -Damn it,Carl!
我不能讲话，因为… 你还讲
惦惦
Can I have the next one,please?
下一组的资料…
Thank you.
谢谢
Joey and Tony Tribbiani.
乔伊和汤尼崔比亚尼
That's us.
我们就是
But this is a study for identical twins.
这是双胞胎的研究
That's right. $2000.
没错，2千大洋
But you're not identical twins.
但你们不是双胞胎
Damn it, Carl!
都是你啦
Oh, my good God.
我的天哪
Continuing the countdown of your favorite meals.
你最爱吃的食物倒数
Tonight, number three:
今晚，第三名
Macaroni and cheese with cut-up hot dogs.
起司通心粉加切丁的热狗
Look,you have done enough. You have to stop this now.
你对我够好了，别再费心了
I will,but not tonight.
我会的，但不是今晚
For dinner music, I thought we could listen to that tape that you made me.
晚餐音乐就来听你录的带子
Oh, the mixed tape.
那卷合辑
"The Way You Look Tonight" is on here.
刚好就是“你今晚的模样”
Dance with me.
陪我跳舞
You are just the sweetest.
你最好最好了
I love the way you look every night, Chandler.
你每晚的模样我都爱，钱德
That's why I made you this tape.
所以我录这卷带子给你
Happy birthday! Love,Janice!
生日快乐，爱你的珍妮丝
No,you're the sweetest.
不，你最好最好了
Okay, ladies, that ends today's class.
好，今天的课到此为止
Remember,be safe out there.
记住，一定要平安
-Great class. -Thanks.
你教得真好 谢谢
I was watching.
我看得很仔细
A couple of questions:
不过我有一些问题
You know that last move...
刚才最后...
where that woman tripped you and pinned you to the floor?
那个女人把你绊倒 压在地上
What would you do next?
你接下来会怎么做？
She'd take the keys and jam them in your..
她会拿钥匙来刺…
No,no. What would you do next?
不是，是你会怎么做？
-Who,me,the attacker? -Yes,that's right.
你是说攻击者？ 是的
Why?
干嘛？
I tried attacking two women. Did not work.
我想偷袭两个女人，却没成功
What?
什么？
No,it's okay. They're my friends.
没关系，她们是我的朋友
In fact,I was married to one of them.
我还跟其中一个结过婚
You attacked your ex-wife?
你偷袭你的前妻？
Oh,no. No,no.
不是…
I tried.
我想偷袭她
But I couldn't. That's why I'm here.
却打不过她，所以才来找你
Maybe we could attack them together!
或许我们可以一起对付她们
That's a no.
你不要
I am so,so,so,so sorry.
非常非常非常对不起
And I will cook anything you want in here...
我会下厨房煮你想吃的菜
and do anything you want in there.
进卧房玩你想玩的花样
Yeah,you will! And are you kidding me?
你当然得煮，你想得美喔
Come on,Monica, it's our Valentine's Day.
别这样，这是我们的情人节
Please,please,please,please?
拜托啦？
Okay.
好吧
我有趣的情人 甜蜜逗趣的情人
-So are we going in there? -I am!
要进房间了吗？ 我要
你的表情如此有趣
Nowhere to run.
你们逃不掉了
I don't like sitting up here. I'm gonna go over..
我不喜欢坐这里，我要过去…
No,they got here first.
是他们先来的
-Why is Ross doing that? -Danger!
罗斯在干嘛？ 危险！
Oh,my God! Why is he jumping on those women?
天哪 他干嘛扑向那两个女人？
We should help them.
我们应该去帮她们
I don't think they need any help.
我看她们不需要帮忙